<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Random Post Generator</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/</link><description>Recent content on Random Post Generator</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 02:54:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rpg.skmobi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>0x9B4B Free Telemetry</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0x9b4b_gcp_metrics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 02:54:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0x9b4b_gcp_metrics/</guid><description>Some time ago I wrote about leveraging GCP free tier for log collection. I also started using it for telemetry though I never updated the post with those details.
Since Google refactored their Monitoring away from that crappy StackDriver interface, it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite nice, so might as well write the setup down (up? ☁️).
Even though GCP monitoring seems oriented to metrics from GCP services it also allows you to create logs-based metrics.</description></item><item><title>0xCF53 Remote, Garage Remote</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0xcf53_rgr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 18:40:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0xcf53_rgr/</guid><description>Dr. No Open One of my garage openers stopped working but I kept it in hope one day I&amp;rsquo;d make a learning exercise out of repairing it.
The other day somehow I brought it up in a conversation and it was highlighted that it is common for the push button to wear out, so I opened the case and tested by shorting over the button with a wire.
And the garage door opened (thanks Dad)!</description></item><item><title>0xF8CB Pi TV - Lock HDMI Configuration</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0xf8cb_pi_tv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 12:31:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0xf8cb_pi_tv/</guid><description>One of my raspberries is connected to the TV (quite original!) running RetroPie with Kodi as well.
Every now and then, power fails. When restored, the Pi always came up with messed up resolution.
I would just reboot it once again and everything would be fine, so I postponed looking into.
Turns out it was one of those things you delay because you think it will take forever to understand but in the end takes 5min&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>0x8490 Privileged Swarm Services</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0x8490_privileged_swarm_service/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 14:38:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0x8490_privileged_swarm_service/</guid><description>Some docker images require extra capabilities to work, ie:
openvpn needs NET_ADMIN anything using USB/i2c will need --device=/dev/ttyAMA0 Swarmkit does not support that (nor the GIEF IT ALL --privileged flag).
There are a lot of issues on their github(s) such as this, this or this.
It seems there is consensus into adding the feature to swarmkit though it won&amp;rsquo;t be available before 19.06 or 19.09.
Until then, the best solution seems to be spinning up a service that starts the container after, such as:</description></item><item><title>0x6BAA OpenVPN Made Easy</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0x6baa_openvpn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 18:54:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0x6baa_openvpn/</guid><description>Why Some people decide to buy some external VPN service for privacy.
Personally, as I already commit all my internet usage to my ISP at home, I rather VPN from untrusted locations into my home instead, saving a few bucks and keeping my ISP as the sole entity holding that information.
I guess I could try to use one of those VPN services (with better privacy terms than my ISP) at home but that would increase complexity too much for the rest of the household</description></item><item><title>0xD755 Free Log Collection</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0xd755_gcp_logging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:47:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0xd755_gcp_logging/</guid><description>I have a few raspberries lying around the house plus a couple of really cheap low-end VPS (1€ arubas)
Not only they there are containers, cron jobs, etc spread among them (but all keep under ansible control) 2 of them are a docker swarm cluster with replicas for same services.
Eventually I need to check logs for something (and I&amp;rsquo;d also like to keep tabs on cpu/memory/disk metrics), so I started looking into log management/collection solutions.</description></item><item><title>0xC53E Peculiar Lenticular</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0xc53e_lenticular/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 18:22:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0xc53e_lenticular/</guid><description>I needed a symbolic gift some time ago and thought a lenticular keychain but the shops I found to get a custom made one would take over 2 weeks to deliver.
Googling a bit for DIY seems the only thing required to print lenticulars is image processing and lenticular lens. Again, getting lenticular lens was not so easy as it looked, so off and found this video, that looks easy!</description></item><item><title>0x0000 The Seed</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0x0000_the_seed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 01:37:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/posts/0x0000_the_seed/</guid><description>Sometimes we need something and we can&amp;rsquo;t find a straight up how-to online.
We put a few pieces together, get it done but wonder if we ever need to do it again, will we find the same resources again? Will they be up? Will we follow the same links?
We want to record our steps to remember later on, but we also want Google to index them so we get there, so why not post them up somewhere?</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rpg.skmobi.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:05:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rpg.skmobi.com/about/</guid><description>Life In Progress</description></item></channel></rss>